[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "How to rename a tag?",
        "answer": "$ git tag new_tag_name old_tag_name<BR>$ git tag -d old_tag_name<BR>$ git push origin :refs/tags/old_tag_name<BR>$ git push --tags"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "How to delete a tag?",
        "answer": "$ git tag -d tag_name<BR>$ git push origin :refs/tags/tag_name<BR>$ git push --tags"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "How to tag a particular commit?",
        "answer": "$ git checkout commit_id<br>$ git tag tag_name<br>$ git push origin tag_name"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "How to set global gitignore?",
        "answer": "$ git config --global core.excludesfile '~/.gitignore'"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "How to setup remote upstream?",
        "answer": "$ git remote add upstream https://github.com/xxx/xxx.git<br>$ git fetch upstream<br>$ git merge upstream/master --ff-only"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "How to search a string in all git branches?",
        "answer": "$ git branch -a | tr -d \\* | sed '/->/d' | xargs git grep search_string"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "How to rename local branch?",
        "answer": "$ git branch -m old_branch_name new_branch_name"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "How to rename remote branch?",
        "answer": "$ git branch -m old_branch_name new_branch_name<br>$ git push origin :old_branch_name new_branch_name<br>$ git checkout new_branch_name<br>$ git branch --unset-upstream<br>$ git push -u origin new_branch_name"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "How to delete remote branch?",
        "answer": "$ git branch -d remote_branch<br>$ git push origin --delete remote_branch"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "How to setup track to remote branch?",
        "answer": "$ git push origin -u new_branch_name"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "How to amend last commit?",
        "answer": "$ git commit --amend -m new_commit_message"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "How to amend last commit with signoff?",
        "answer": "$ git commit --amend -s<br>$ git push origin branch_name --force"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "How to find diff against stash?",
        "answer": "$ git stash show -p stash@{0}"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "How to delete un-staged changes while keep stage one?",
        "answer": "$ git stash save --keep-index<br>$ git stash drop"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "How to apply stashed changes and remove from the list?",
        "answer": "$ git stash pop stash@{0}"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "How to apply stashed changes and keep it in the list?",
        "answer": "$ git stash apply stash@{0}"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "How to look for branch locally or remotely?",
        "answer": "$ git branch --contains branch_name<br>$ git branch -r --contains branch_name"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "How to delete a file from a branch?",
        "answer": "$ git rm file_name<br>$ git commit"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "How to move a file to another folder?",
        "answer": "$ git mv file_name another_folder"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "How to revert back merge?",
        "answer": "$ git reset --hard last_commit_id_before_the_merge"
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "question": "How to revert a commit?",
        "answer": "$ git revert commit_id"
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "question": "How to clone a repository?",
        "answer": "$ git clone path_to_git_repository"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "question": "How to cherry pick a commit?",
        "answer": "$ git cherry-pick commit_id -x -s"
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "question": "How to find diff against cached?",
        "answer": "$ git diff --cached file_name"
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "question": "How to diff against another branch?",
        "answer": "$ git diff another_branch_name"
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "question": "How to diff between two commits?",
        "answer": "$ git diff commit_id_1..commit_id_2"
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "question": "How to get history of file?",
        "answer": "$ git log -- file_name"
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "question": "How to create formatted patch?",
        "answer": "$ git format-patch -1 branch_1 branch_2 file_name"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "question": "How to apply patch?",
        "answer": "$ git apply --stat file.patch<br>$ git apply --check file.patch<br>$ git am --signoff < file.patch"
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "question": "How to rebase feature branch?",
        "answer": "$ git checkout feature-branch<br>$ git rebase -i master-branch"
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "question": "How to selectively add changes?",
        "answer": "$ git add -p"
    },
    {    "id": 32,
         "question": "How to add remote shortcuts?",
         "answer": "Add the following two lines to your local git config:<br><br>[url \"https://github.com/manwar/\"]<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;insteadOf = manwar:<br><br>and then you can do something like:<br><br>$ git checkout manwar:Map-Tube"
    },
    {    "id": 33,
         "question": "How to pull PR from upstream?",
         "answer": "Setup upstream, if not already done. Then checkout new branch. Finally run this command:<br><br>$ git pull upstream pull/PR-ID/head"
    }
]
